<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>shortcodes on Coding Dayz</title>
    <link>https://gloc-mike.github.io/tags/shortcodes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in shortcodes on Coding Dayz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>**© 2023 Michael Ball. All rights reserved.**</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 23:20:37 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gloc-mike.github.io/tags/shortcodes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Escaping Hugo Shortcodes in Posts</title>
      <link>https://gloc-mike.github.io/2020-/08-/14/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 23:20:37 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gloc-mike.github.io/2020-/08-/14/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR
Add /* after the opening shortcode tags i.e., {{&amp;lt; and */ before the closing shortcode tags i.e. &amp;gt;}}
While creating the post Beautifulhugo Theme Extras - Shortcodes (Split), I had quite a bit of trouble finding the answer to the question of &amp;ldquo;how can I display a block code in my post?&amp;rdquo;.
The answer seemed obvious, use a code fence i.e. use triple backticks; OR indent the code block using 4 spaces; OR after adding a colon (:), surround the code by two blank lines, one at the top and one below the last line of code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beautifulhugo Theme Extras - Shortcodes (Split)</title>
      <link>https://gloc-mike.github.io/2020-/08-/13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 22:34:32 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gloc-mike.github.io/2020-/08-/13/</guid>
      <description>Another extra beautifulhugo theme shortcode is called split. This shortcode splits the page into two columns. The example shown in the doco in the beautifulhugo repo (at the time of writing) was a little confusing because the closing endcolumns tag was incorrect (missing an s). Got there in the end. 😅
It should look like this:
1 2 3 4 5 {{&amp;lt; columns &amp;gt;}} First column on the right side of the page {{&amp;lt; column &amp;gt;}} Second column on the left side of the page {{&amp;lt; endcolumns &amp;gt;}} Yes, the first tag is columns whereas the intermediate tag is column.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beautifulhugo Theme Extras - Shortcodes (Details)</title>
      <link>https://gloc-mike.github.io/2020-/08-/12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 22:29:32 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gloc-mike.github.io/2020-/08-/12/</guid>
      <description>An extra beautifulhugo theme shortcode is called details (checking the code itself shows that it is based on the HTML &amp;lt;details&amp;gt; tag). This shortcode hides some content until the text set on the detail is clicked.
An example follows:
Click here to expand to show hidden content! This is the content you&amp;rsquo;d like to hide. 🧘
The actual code used in this post for the previous example looks like this:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
